The nice thing about war is that the person who kills you
really has nothing against you. Personally.
Catch-22 is a war, comedy film directed by Mike Nichols.
A WWII military pilot makes a valiant effort to be certified
insane in order to be excused from flying missions.
But there's a catch.
Capt. John Yossarian, played by Alan Arkin.
Col. Cathcart, played by Martin Balsam.
Maj. Danby, played by Richard Benjamin.
Capt. Nately, played by Art Garfunkel.
Dr. "Doc" Daneeka, played by Jack Gilford.
Lt. Col. Korn, played by Buck Henry.
Catch-22 is a 1970 American satirical comedy war film adapted from
the 1961 novel of the same name by Joseph Heller.
In creating a black comedy revolving around the "lunatic characters" of Heller's satirical anti-war novel set at a fictional Mediterranean base during World War II, director
Mike Nichols and screenwriter Buck Henry (also in the cast) worked on the film script for two years, converting Heller's complex novel to the medium of film.
The cast included Alan Arkin, Bob Balaban, Martin Balsam, Richard Benjamin, Italian actress Olimpia Carlisi, French comedian Marcel Dalio, Art Garfunkel in his
acting debut, Jack Gilford, Charles Grodin, Bob Newhart, Anthony Perkins, Austin Pendleton, Paula Prentiss, Martin Sheen, Jon Voight, and Orson Welles.
Garfunkel's songwriting partner Paul Simon also
appeared, but his scenes were cut.
The film explores themes of suicide, island, based on
novel or book, fascism, world war ii.
The tone is lighthearted.